A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President, Series 12 FA359
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President, Series 12
1972-1973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Republican Party (N.Y.). State Committee
FA359
2.35 Cubic Feet 6 boxes
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 12
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents note
This small series contains only a portion of the files of the New York State Committee to Reelect the President [Nixon]. The original extent of the materials was twelve cubic feet. However, shortly after the materials were deposited in the Rockefeller Family Archives, the NYS Committee to Reelect the President (NYS CREEP) was audited by the Internal Revenue Service. The majority of the materials was sent to Washington, DC, and was never returned. The original folder listing of the full collection of 12 boxes is in Box 2, Folder 14. The remaining materials--which comprise this series--were originally found in boxes 9, 10, and 11.
These fragmentary materials document aspects of the 1972 presidential election, the last election prior to more stringent campaign finance laws taking effect. Among these remaining materials are receipts for contributions made to NYS CREEP. There are also cancelled administrative checks indicating the costs associated with running a presidential campaign. However, as noted in the attached separation sheet, specific tax documents pertaining to NYS CREEP staff have been removed and destroyed by the Rockefeller Archive Center.
As Governor of New York, Nelson Rockefeller took a prominent role in the 1972 presidential election, although Rockefeller and President Nixon were long-time political rivals. There is no evidence in this material, however, of any direct involvement by Nelson A. Rockefeller in NYS CREEP.
Civil service -- New York (State); Civil service; Federal government -- United States; Economics; Arms control -- United States; Arms control; Civil defense -- United States; Civil defense; Public policy; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; State governments -- United States; Public relations; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Government policy; United States; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Political science; Political campaigns -- United States; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Presidential campaigns -- United States; International economic relations; Human rights; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Legislation -- New York (State); Latin America; International relations -- United States; International relations
- General Information (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Stationery, letter of incorporation, list of directors and members of New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP).
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, September 10, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, October 16, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, October 16, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, October 26, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, October 26, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Report of Receipts and Expenditures to United States Comptroller General, January 31, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Payroll Changes (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Forms, correspondence, and memoranda on New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) staff salaries and adjustments.
- Tax Information (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Forms, instructions and information on federal tax issues.
- W-4 Forms (A-L) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Correspondence and memoranda on New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) staff.
  Appraisal note
  Actual W-4 forms have been removed and destroyed.
- W-4 Forms (A-L) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- W-4 Forms (M-Z) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- W-4 Forms (M-Z) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Original Box and Folder Listing from NYS Committee to Reelect the President (Box 2, Folder 14)
- New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) - Cancelled Payroll and Expense Checks (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Adding Machine Tapes (Box 3, Folder 15)
- New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) - Cancelled Adminstrative Checks (Box 4, Folder 16)
- New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) - Contribution Receipts (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Yellow copies, numbered (all numbers not included).
- New York State Committee to Reelect the President (CREEP) - Contribution Receipts (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Pink copies, numbered (all receipts not included).